Guide to the Bob Wethern Papers 1900-2006
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Bob Wethern Papers
1900-2006
bulk 1920-2006
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 726
Wethern, Robert E.
26 Linear Feet of Shelf Space 50 boxes
Bob Wethern (1921-2008) was a journalist and writter based in the Pacific Northwest. This collection consists primarily of Bob Wethern's research materials, notes, and drafts related to two substantial but unfinished writing projects.
Bob Wethern (1921-2008) was born in Walla Walla, Washington to Milton and Rita Wethern. After attending schools in Washington and Minnesota, he entered the University of Idaho, where he majored in journalism. While a student, he became the sports editor of the Daily Idahonian.
Beginning in 1946 Wethern worked as a reporter and photographer at the Bremerton Sun, leaving in 1957 to take a position at the National Association of Manufacturers in Portland, Oregon, where he remained until his retirement in 1979.
Wethern's interest in sports and outdoor writing extended beyond his work as a journalist, and continued throughout his life. He edited a series of angling histories, the Rivers of Oregon, and played an important role in preparing the work of other writers for publication, including Lee Richardson and Robert H. Smith.
He was a charter member of the Flyfishers Club of Oregon, and also belonged to the Tau Epsilon fraternity, the Oregon Society of Association Executives, Toastmasters International, the Tacoma Club, the Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks, and the Federation of Fly Fishermen.
This collection consists primarily of Bob Wethern's research materials, notes, and drafts related to two substantial but unfinished writing projects. Most of this material consists of reproductions (annotated photocopies and photographic reproductions) collected for a project Wethern undertook in partnership with artist David Hagerbaumer. This project, "The Waterfowler's Pacific Flyway," was planned as a work of anecdotes and history framed geographically by the Pacific flyway. This migratory path of birds, mostly waterfowl, stretches from the Arctic region in the far north to Central America in the south. The files for Wethern's flyway project include correspondence; documentation from interviews; newspapers and other printed material; copies of archival documents; files of historical materials collected by Wethern; photographs; and manuscript drafts of some sections and chapters.
The second project, "Tackle Counter Tales," was planned as a published collection of fishing and hunting anecdotes. Wethern divided the project into two parts, "Hunting Humor" and "Fishing Funnies." The files for this unfinished project include Wethern's notes and collected research materials, as well as drafts.
Note about dates: in the Container List below, the dates given for photocopied materials generally reflect the dates of Wethern's research activity, when the material was reproduced and the copies were collected, rather than the dates of the original items.
Some documents in this collection were received in unstable condition, mainly due to deteriorating adhesives. These items were photocopied, and the originals discarded.
The collection is arranged with two main series, each including material related to a major research and writing project. Wethern's original filing system reflected this organization for most of his papers, and the rest was sorted into these series during processing. In cases where files were not clearly associated with one of the two projects, they were placed in the series that seemed most closely related.
Photographs that Wethern filed separately from related research materials have been grouped together in the third series; other photographs, which were mingled with related materials, were left in Wethern's filing order to preserve contextual information.
The fourth series consists of an index card file with Wethern's project notes, and computer diskettes with word processing files.
Series 1: Tackle Counter Tales (TCT), 1920-2006. This series contains material related to a planned collection of hunting and fishing anecdotes. It includes interview transcripts and notes, correspondence, printed material (primarily newspaper and magazine clippings), photocopies, photographs, notes and drafts, and historical materials collected by Wethern. There are also several files related to Wethern's assistance with the early stages of Robert H. Smith's book, Native Trout of North America (1984). There is no particular arrangement in this series; Wethern's files on individuals, general subjects, and special topics are intermixed.
Series 2: The Waterfowler's Pacific Flyway (TWPF), 1953-2003. This series contains interview transcripts and notes, correspondence, printed material (primarily newspaper and magazine clippings), photocopies of archival documents, and photographs. There are also manuscript drafts for many chapters. With the exception of some materials organized topically, this series is arranged in a roughly geographical sequence from south to north by region, state, or province, beginning with coastal areas and continuing with inland areas.
Series 3: Photographs, 1900-1990 (bulk 1979-1990). This series contains photographic images in a variety of formats (slides, prints, negatives, photocopies), primarily reproductions of photographs from archival collections gathered by Wethern for Tackle Counter Tales and the Waterfowler's Pacific Flyway. Other photographs, which were mingled with related materials, were left in Wethern's filing order to preserve contextual information and are located in Series 1 and 2.
Series 4: Index card file and computer diskettes, circa 1980-1990. This series consists of an index card file with Wethern's project notes, and computer diskettes with word processing files.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Bob Wethern donated these papers to the Washington State University Libraries in 2005 (MS 2005-15).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Wethern, Robert E. -- Archives
Waterfowl.; Birds -- Migration -- Pacific Coast (North America); Fowling -- Anecdotes.; Fishing -- Anecdotes.; Hunting -- Anecdotes.; Hunting and fishing clubs -- History.
Fisheries and Wildlife; Journalism; Oregon; Washington (State); Idaho; Alaska; Montana; British Columbia
- Series 1: Tackle Counter Tales, 1964-2006
  - Poaching, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sporting goods, including firearms, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Saltwater lures (includes fishing derby information), circa 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Roy A. Holland manuscript about fishing, circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Northern Commercial, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Klineburgers (Gene and Burt Klineburger, Klineburger Brothers Inc.), 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Langtry's Gunn Story ("Gunn's Gun"), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - W. F. Sheard, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Frederic Leopold, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Those Were The Days kudos." Correspondence and printed articles praising Lee Richardson's book (edited by Wethern), 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Don Bates manuscript and correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Don Bates, Sr. Correspondence and other items, primarily about marine vessels and insurance, and some material about hunting dogs, 1920-1939 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Don Bates and H. R. MacMillan, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Don Bates correspondence and related materials, 1973-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
  - Fred Auger, 1973-1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - A. P. (Gus) Craig, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - A. P. (Gus) Craig, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Grenold Collins, primarily Alaska topics including aviation, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
  - Fred Locke scrapbook, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mike Croft, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Orvis, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Issues of "Flyline," newsletter of the Flyfishers Club of Oregon, 2000-2005 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - William E. Scripture, Jr. (correspondence about manuscript), 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Fred Locke, 1981-2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Bob Smith book project files (manuscripts and typescripts with editorial annotations, supporting documentation and related correspondence, all related to Robert H. Smith's book, Native Trout of North America), 1984, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 29-34)
  - Bob Smith book project files, 1979-1981 (continued) (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - King County, WA. Correspondence, notes and clippings about individuals and businesses, circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - San Juan County, WA, circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Snohomish County, WA, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - North Puget Sound, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Whatcom County, WA, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Pierce County, WA, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Kitsap County, WA, circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Clallam County, WA, 1981-1988 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Mason County, WA, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Cowlitz County, WA, circa early 1980s (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Wahkiakum County, WA, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Clark County, WA, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Washington correspondence and related items, 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Pacific County, WA, circa early 1980s (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Olympia, WA, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Pacific County, WA, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Lewis County, WA, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Jefferson County WA, circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Thurston County, WA, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Skamania County, WA (copy of article about first ascent of Mt. Saint Helens), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Klickitat County, WA, circa 1976 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Walla Walla, WA, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Cle Elum, WA, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Walla Walla area, 1978-1986 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - "Dayton, etc." (includes Dayton and other locations in Eastern Washington), 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Yakima, WA area, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Ellensburg, WA, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Yakima, WA, 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Northeast Washington (Spokane, Wenatchee, etc.), 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Miscellaneous (notes), circa 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Miscellaneous Eastern Washington, circa 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Miscellaneous Eastern Washington (continued), circa 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Western Oregon, circa 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Northern California, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - San Francisco, CA, 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Washington State, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Hawaii, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Southern California, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Colorado hunting and fishing guides (newspapers), circa 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Alaska fishing, circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Alaska, 1966-1981 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Alaska, 1980-1987 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Texas, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Nevada, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Mexico and South America, circa 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Montana, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Colorado, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 83-84)
  - Gunnison County, CO, 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Nevada, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Idaho miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Idaho, 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Wyoming, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Moscow, ID, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Arizona, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 91-92)
  - New Mexico, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Inland Corridor, Klamath-Modoc Indians, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Hawaii, circa 1980-1985 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Hunting, general, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Tacoma and Olympia, WA, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Portland, OR, 1980-1985 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - "Wardens, Keepers, Poachers, Hijackers," 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - "Hunting and Fishing as a Catalyst for: solving crimes, finding ore, etc.," circa 1980-1986 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - "Ironic and Unusual Incidents," 1980-1990 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - "Meat Mixups, intentional and otherwise," 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - "Days of Plenty" and predator contests before harvest restrictions, circa 1980-1986 (Box 12, Folder 103-104)
  - "Dogs: remarkable and otherwise," 1984-1989 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - "Practical Jokes on self, partners," 1983-1990 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - "Crack Shots," "Miss by a mile," 1980-1986 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - "Quotable Quotes," 1976-1987 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - Phony fishing derbies, fish in unusual locations, fishing under odd conditions, 1978-1983 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - "Incidents with Indians," 1981 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - "Honest" exaggerations, 1977-2006 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Taxidermy anecdotes, 1973-1985 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Decoys, circa 1980-1986 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Politics of early day hunting and fishing, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Miscellaneous anecdotes, 1982-1985 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Miscellaneous anecdotes, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - "Tackle Counter Encounters and other super-salesmanship by tackle jocks," 1980-1985 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - "Wildlife farms and trophy temples," 1982 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Oregon fishing history, 1980-1983 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - State files, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Allen, Henry, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Ashton, Gen. J. M., circa 1980-1986 (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - Bratz, Lou Jr., 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - Dwelley, Charles and Joseph Kemmerich, "Brown" Wiseman (Upper Skagit Valley), 1983 (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - Green, Joshua, 1984-1985 (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Hegg and Hegg and Lawman, William A., 1983 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - Johnson, Walt (WA), 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - Judson, Phoebe, circa 1980-1986 (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - Kawahara, Hippo, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - Klineburger Bros, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 130)
  - Markham, John, circa 1980-1986 (Box 15, Folder 131)
  - Meyers, Bud (guide), 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 132)
  - Simmons Family, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 133)
  - Smith, Leroy (Port. Angeles), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 134)
  - Truman, Harry (Mt. Saint Helens), circa 1980-1986 (Box 15, Folder 135)
  - Josie Warner Minser, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 136)
  - Wilhelm, Honor L., circa 1980-1986 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Wilsons, Rocky and Lenore and other Upper Skagit pioneers, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Yeager, Ira (Bellingham, WA), 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Zarkades, Gus and Bill Nifores (WA), 1980 (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (WA), 1978-1984 (Box 15, Folder 141-142)
  - Poaching (WA), newspaper clippings, 1978-1984 (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Where Would You Go? by Ben Hur Lampman (book and related documentation), 1975 and 2003 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - "The Creel," volume 7, number 1, 1969 December (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Montana, 1980-1985 (Box 16, Folder 146-148)
  - Grays Harbor County, 1978-1984 (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - "Oldtimers Outdoorsman Reunion," 1982-1985 (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - Eddie and "Stine" Bauer photographs, undated (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Idaho Historical Society (photocopies); miscellaneous notes and drafts, circa 1982 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Miscellaneous fishing articles, 1966-1981 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - British Columbia miscellaneous, 1985-1988 (Box 17, Folder 155)
  - British Columbia and other Canada, 1983-1986 (Box 17, Folder 156.1-156.2)
  - British Columbia, circa 1980-1986 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - British Columbia miscellaneous, circa 1980-1985 (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - Yukon (mostly printed ephemera), 1975-1981 (Box 18, Folder 159)
  - British Columbia, 1974-1987 (Box 18, Folder 160.1-160.2)
  - British Columbia, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 161)
  - British Columbia, 1981-1988 (Box 18, Folder 162.1-162.2)
  - British Columbia, circa 1980-1985 (Box 18, Folder 163)
  - Pacific Northwest wilderness, 1980-1984 (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - Idaho hunters, 1981-1987 (Box 19, Folder 165)
  - Idaho, 1980-1985 (Box 19, Folder 166-169)
  - Mountain men, 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 170)
  - Utah sporting, 1978-1981 (Box 19, Folder 171)
  - Utah, 1980-1985 (Box 19, Folder 172-174)
  - Utah, 1980-1985 (continued) (Box 20, Folder 175)
  - Alaska articles, note, etc., 1988 (Box 20, Folder 176)
  - Ben Paris, Seattle, 1980-1984 (Box 20, Folder 177)
  - Eddie and Stine Bauer, 1980-1983 (Box 20, Folder 178)
  - Marcus Nalley, 1982-1984 (Box 20, Folder 179)
  - McKenzie River photographs, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 180)
  - Raleigh W. "Bill" Cady, Jr., and miscellaneous, 1965-1982 (Box 20, Folder 181)
  - "Survival to Sport," correspondence, notes, and photographs, 1980-1986 (Box 20, Folder 182)
  - British Columbia, 1981-1983 (Box 20, Folder 183)
  - Victoria, B.C., 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 184)
  - British Columbia contacts, 1980-1986 (Box 20, Folder 185)
  - "Miscellaneous Lower 48" (primarily correspondence with Gary Topping), 1966-2001 (Box 20, Folder 186-187)
  - Alaska, circa 1980-1986 (Box 20, Folder 188.1)
  - Alaska, circa 1980-1986 (continued) (Box 21, Folder 188.2)
- Series 2: The Waterfowler's Pacific Flyway (TWPF), 1953-2003
  - San Quintin (Mexico-Baja California), 1990 (Box 21, Folder 189)
  - Gary Kramer (manager, Sacramento National Wildlife Refuge, CA), 1990 (Box 21, Folder 190)
  - Ricardo A. Rocha, Hermosillo (Mexico), 1990 (Box 21, Folder 191)
  - Mexico-Baja California, 1977-1986 (Box 21, Folder 192)
  - Mexico-Baja California, circa 1981-1990 (Box 21, Folder 193-194)
  - Mexico-Baja California, 1986-1990 (Box 21, Folder 195)
  - Baja California, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 196)
  - Southern California-Mexico (includes TWPF section "No Return"), 1986-1990 (Box 21, Folder 197-198)
  - Miscellaneous (mostly CA), undated (Box 22, Folder 199)
  - "Active Southern California," 1965-1989 (Box 22, Folder 200)
  - Southern California, circa 1985-1990 (Box 22, Folder 201-203)
  - Southern California, 1985-1989 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - Southern California, coastal and inland, 1981-1986 (Box 23, Folder 205)
  - Southern California, 1983-1990 (Box 23, Folder 206)
  - San Diego Bay, CA, 1975-1991 (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Southern California (Los Angeles), 1980-1990 (Box 23, Folder 208-209)
  - Los Angeles, CA, 1979-1982 (Box 23, Folder 210)
  - Los Angeles area (Costa Mesa, Santa Ana, CA), 1986-1987 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - Venice Island Duck Club (CA), 1986-1991 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - Cerritos Gun Club (CA), circa 1985-1990 (Box 23, Folder 213)
  - Bear Valley (CA) duck hunting, circa 1985-1990 (Box 23, Folder 214)
  - Southern California waterfowl, 1980-1986 (Box 23, Folder 215)
  - Mira Monte (CA) stories (includes TWPF manuscript section), circa 1986-1990 (Box 23, Folder 216)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, some with R. K. Rebele, (CA) 1986-1988 (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - Central California coast, circa 1985-1990 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Central and Northern California, 1986-1993 (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Central California (coastal and inland), 1980-1986 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - "Active" Northern California (includes some Western Washington material), 1980-1989 (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Northern California, circa 1985-1990 (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - Northern California, 1985-1990 (Box 24, Folder 223)
  - Northern California "Once reviewed," circa 1985-1990 (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - Northern Bay area, CA, 1980-1988 (Box 24, Folder 225)
  - San Francisco Bay area (Orinda, Antioch, Carmel), 1988-1990 (Box 25, Folder 226)
  - Suisun, CA (photocopies of nineteenth century articles), undated (Box 25, Folder 227)
  - San Francisco Bay, CA, circa 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 228)
  - San Francisco Bay area (pre-1950), 1986 (Box 25, Folder 229)
  - San Francisco area, CA, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 230)
  - Northern coastal California, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 231)
  - Northern coastal California (pre-1930), circa 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 232)
  - Del Norte County, CA, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 233)
  - Del Norte and Mendocino counties, CA (includes TWPF manuscript section: introduction for Northern California Coast chapter), circa 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 234)
  - Humboldt County, CA, 1986-1991 (Box 25, Folder 235)
  - Humboldt Bay Environmental Assessment (CA), 1989 (Box 25, Folder 236)
  - Humboldt Bay, CA, and miscellaneous, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 237)
  - Humboldt Bay, Eureka, CA, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 238)
  - Humboldt Fish and Game Club (CA), 1991 (Box 25, Folder 239)
  - Humboldt Fish and Game Club (CA), 1985 (Box 26, Folder 240-241)
  - Stockton and Sacramento, CA, 1987-1990 (Box 26, Folder 242)
  - Sacramento National Wildlife Refuge, 1988-1990 (Box 26, Folder 243)
  - Environmental Assessment, Proposed Sacramento River National Wildlife Preserve (printed report), 1989 (Box 26, Folder 244)
  - Great Central Valley (Willows, Marysville, Sacramento), 1985 (Box 26, Folder 245)
  - San Joaquin Valley, CA (Stockton, Modesto, Guisline, Los Banos), circa 1985-1990 (Box 26, Folder 246)
  - Lake County, CA, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 247)
  - Willows, CA, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 248)
  - Northern California inland, 1986-1989 (Box 26, Folder 249)
  - Inland Corridor--Northern California, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 250)
  - Northern inland California, 1984-1987 (Box 26, Folder 251)
  - Gil Berg: San Bruno and Willows, CA, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 252)
  - TWPF manuscript section (chapter and notes): "The No Name Club, A Downtown Affair," 1991 (Box 26, Folder 253)
  - Northern California and Southern Oregon (also includes other locations), 1986-1991 (Box 26, Folder 254)
  - Northern California and Southern Oregon (continued) (Box 27, Folder 255)
  - "Tule Fog," CA, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 256)
  - J. Goldsborough Bruff (CA), circa 1985-1990 (Box 27, Folder 257)
  - John C. Fremont, circa 1985-1990 (Box 27, Folder 258)
  - "Ishi the Last Yahi" (CA), circa 1985-1990 (Box 27, Folder 259)
  - John Sutter and Peter Lassen (CA), 1990 (Box 27, Folder 260)
  - William Weinrich (CA), 1990 (Box 27, Folder 261)
  - Southern Oregon, 1982-1986 (Box 27, Folder 262)
  - Klamath County, OR, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 263)
  - Klamath County, OR, 1982-1988 (Box 27, Folder 264)
  - "Rathje Rumble II," Klamath Falls, OR, 1986-2003 (Box 27, Folder 265)
  - "Rathje Rumble II," Burns, OR, 1983-1990 (Box 27, Folder 266)
  - Martin Rathje, 1980-2003 (Box 28, Folder 267)
  - Jackson County, OR, 1981-1988 (Box 28, Folder 268)
  - Jackson County, OR, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 269)
  - Curry County, OR, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 270)
  - Douglas County, OR, circa 1985-1990 (Box 28, Folder 271)
  - Lane County, OR (coastal only), 1986 (Box 28, Folder 272)
  - Benton County, OR, 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 273)
  - Linn County, OR, 1986-1987 (Box 28, Folder 274)
  - Marion County, OR, 1985-1988 (Box 28, Folder 275)
  - Washington County, OR, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 276)
  - Multnomah County, OR, 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 277-278)
  - Yamhill, OR, 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 279)
  - Sauvie Island, OR, 1983-1988 (Box 28, Folder 280)
  - Columbia County, OR, 1983-1988 (Box 28, Folder 281-282)
  - Northern Oregon, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 283)
  - Coos County, OR, 1986-1989 (Box 28, Folder 284)
  - Tillamook County, OR, 1985-1989 (Box 28, Folder 285)
  - Mid-state Oregon, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 286)
  - Clatsop County Duck Hunters Association, 1981-1983 (Box 29, Folder 287)
  - Seaside, OR, 1984-1988 (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - Astoria, OR, 1985-1988 (Box 29, Folder 289)
  - Astoria, OR, 1973-1988 (Box 29, Folder 290-291)
  - Astoria, OR, area. Mostly copies of minutes of the Clatsop County Duck Hunters Association; 1940-1960, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 292)